帅哥 你好吗?
Hey,gorgeous. How's it going?
在日光灯底下吃着日本泡面
Dehydrated Japanese noodles under fluorescent lights.
我能有多好?
Does it get better than this?
问个问题 你没有约会对象 是吧?
Question:You're not dating anybody, are you?
因为我遇见一个 超适合你的完美对象
Because I met somebody who would be perfect for you.
完美可能会有点不恰当
You see, perfect might be a problem.
你可以说是互相依赖 或自我毁灭
Had you said codependent or selfdestructive...
你星期六想去约会吗?      是的，很想
You want a date Saturday?        Yes, please.
他很可爱
He is cute.
他很好笑 他      他是男的?
He's funny.He's...        He's a he?
是啊 天哪
Well, yeah.
天啊 我只是
Oh. God. I just...
你很棒  天啊
You're nice. Oh, God.
很好 雪莉 我实在是没脸见人
Good, Shelly. Okay. I'm just gonna go flush myself down the toilet now.
好 再见
Okay. Byebye.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧
《老友记》蓝光版 第01季 第08集
调校制作：寒 枫
字幕编辑：阿 汨
奶奶死了两次
The One Where Nana Dies Twice
经过那件事之后 真的很难继续享受拉面
It's hard to enjoy a cup of noodles after that.
很夸张对吧?
Is that ridiculous?
你们能相信 她真的这样认为吗?
Can you believe she actually thought that?
可以
Yeah.
我刚认识你的时候 我想说或许
Well,I mean, when I first met you, I thought maybe...
有可能
possibly...
你可能是
you might be.
真的?
You did?
但后来你在菲比的生日派对上
Then you spent Phoebe's birthday party
对着我的胸部说话…
talking to my breasts...
所以我想说应该不是
So then I figured maybe not.
你们其他人刚认识我的时候 有那么想过吗?
Huh. Did, uh, any of the rest of you guys think that when you first met me?
我有      我想有
I did.        I think so.
我没有      不...我也没有
Not me.        No, no, me neither.
不过大学时期的苏珊有那想过
Although, uh, back in college, Susan Saladore did.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding.
那你有跟她说我不是吗?      没有
Did you tell her I wasn't?        No.
因为我想跟她交往
It's because I kind of wanted to go out with her too.
所以我跟她说 你那时正在和伯尼交往...
So I told her, actually, you were seeing Bernie Speliman...
也就是另一个喜欢她的家伙
who also liked her.
这真是奇怪了
Well, this is fascinating.
那是什么原因?
So, uh, what is it about me?
我不知道 因为你很聪明 风趣
I don't know. Because you're smart, you're funny.
罗斯也是啊 你们有想过他是吗?
Ross is smart and funny. You ever think that about him?
是啊      那到底是什么原因?
Yeah, right.        What is it?
我不知道 你就是 你有种特质
Okay, I don't know. You just...You have a quality.
没错      对，某种特质
Yes, exactly.        Right? Yeah, a quality.
"特质" 很好 我还担心你们会说得很模糊
"A quality." Good. I was worried you were gonna be vague about this.
喂?
Hello?
瑞秋 是巴洛从罗马打来的
Oh. Rachel. It's Paolo calling from Rome.
天啊 他从罗马打来
Oh, my God. Calling from Rome.
他从罗马打来 我也做得到啊
So he's calling from Rome. I could do that.
只要去罗马就行了
Just gotta go to Rome.
莫妮卡 你爸刚打进来 你可以讲快一点吗
Monica, your dad just beeped in. Can you make it quick?
我在跟罗马通话
I'm talking to Rome.
跟我通话的人在罗马
爸 什么事?
Hey, Dad. What's up?
天哪
Oh, God.
罗斯 是外婆
Ross, it's Nana.
嗨
Hey.
你们好吗?      嘿，爸
How you doing?         Hey, Dad.
她还好吗?
So, uh, how's she doing?
医生说只剩几小时了
The doctor says it's a matter of hours.
你还好吗 妈?      我? 我很好
How are you, Mom?         Me? I'm fine, fine.
我很高兴你来了
I'm glad you're here.
你的头发怎么了?
What's with your hair?
什么?
What?
有什么不同?
What's different?
没有啊
Nothing.
噢 也许吧
Oh, maybe that's it.
她实在是令人难以置信 她母亲...
She's unbelievable. Her mother's...
好了 放轻松点
Okay, relax, relax.
看来我们还要在这里 待一段时问
We are gonna be here a while. It looks like.
免不了还要谈你男友和工作的事
We still have boyfriends and your career to cover.
天啊
Oh. God.
她皮包里有发霉的薄荷糖
The fuzzy little mints at the bottom of her purse.
对 超恶心的
Yeah, they were gross.
你们知道我最爱什么吗?
Oh, you know what I love?
她的代糖
Her Sweet'n Lows.
她老是从餐厅偷代糖
And she was always stealing them from restaurants.
不只是餐厅 还有我们家
Not just restaurants, from our house.
盖勒太太?
Mrs. Geller?
她看起来好小
She looks so small.
我知道
I know.
至少她现在有外公和菲利斯婶婶陪着了
Well, at least she's with PopPop and Aunt Phyllis now.
再见了 外婆
Goodbye, Nana.
别了 外婆
Bye, Nana.
罗斯!
Ross!
护士
Nurse.
怎么了?
What is going on?
护士不是说外婆走了吗?
You know, uh, how the nurse said Nana had passed?
但并不是
Well, she's not quite.
什么?      她还没走
What?        She's not passed.
她还在 她活过来了
She's present. She's back.
怎么了?
What's going on?
她可能死了
She may have died.
她可能死了?
"She may have died"?
我们还在观察
We're looking into it.
我进去看看
Uh, I'll go see.
这几乎是从未有过的事
This almost never happens.
现在她去世了
Now she's passed.
我一定得知道
I just have to know, okay?
是我的头发吗?
Is it my hair?
没错 钱德 就是这样 你的头发
Yes, Chandler, that's exactly what it is. It's your hair.
对 你长了一头同性恋式的头发
Yeah, you have homosexual hair.
嗨        嗨
Hey.        Hi.
那她...
So did she...?
两次
Twice.
真是糟透了
Oh, that sucks.
你们还好吗?
You guys okay?
我不知道 感觉好怪
I don't know. It's weird.
我知道她走了 但我就是没有感觉到...
I know she's gone, but I just don't feel, uh...
或许是因为 她没有真的离开
Maybe that's because she's not really gone.
不 她走了
No, no, she's gone.
我们检查过
We checked.
很多次
A lot.
我是说 或许没有人曾真正离去
No, I mean, maybe no one ever really goes.
自从我妈死后 我偶尔…
Ever since my mom died, every now and then..
还是会感觉到她就在这里 你知道吗
I get this feeling that she's, like, right here, you know?
还有我初中最好的朋友 黛比
Oh. And Debbie, my best friend from junior high...
在打迷你高尔夫球时 被闪电击中
got struck by lightning on a miniature golf course.
用黄色的铅笔时
I always get this really strong Debbie vibe...
我总是能强烈的感应到黛比
...whenever I use one of those little yellow pencils.
我好想她
I miss her.
菲比 你想要这个吗?
Aw. Here. Pheobe. Want this?
噢 谢了      不客气
Oh, thanks.        Sure.
我今早才把它削尖的
I just sharpened her this morning.
我完全不相信那一套 你死掉后
See I don'tbelieve any of that. I think when you're dead...
就是死了 消失了 成了虫子的食物
...you're dead. You're gone. You're worm food.
钱德看起来很像同志对吧?
So Chandler looks gay, huh?
我不知道这是谁 但绝不是黛比
I don'tknow who this is, but it's not Debbie.
我以为要用密封的棺木
I thought it's gonna be a closed casket.
这不代表她不能穿漂亮点
Well, that doesn't mean she can't look nice.
孩子 你觉得自己能钻进去吗
Sweetie, you think you can get in there?
当然可以
I don't see why not.
我的牙齿矫正器在这里
Here's my retainer
我一直在想
I was just thinking...
轮到我的时候      爸
...when my time comes...       Dad.
听我说
Listen to me.
轮到我的时候 我想海葬
When my time comes, I wanna be buried at sea.
什么?
You what?
我想葬在海里 看起来很好玩
I wanna be buried at sea. It looks like fun.
解释一下好玩的意思
Define "fun."
别这样 那一天你们会很开心的
Come on. You'll make a day of it.
租艘船 带上午餐…
You'll get a boat, pack a lunch...
然后把你的尸体丢到海里 天啊 听起来真好玩
And then we throw your body in the water. Gee, that does sound fun.
大家都以为他们很了解我
Everyone thinks they know me.
大家都说 "杰克盖勒循规蹈矩"
Everyone says, "Jack Geller so predictable."
或许我走后 他们会说 "海葬?"
Maybe after I'm gone,they'll say, "Buried at sea? Huh."
可能他们会这样说
That's probably what they'll say.
我喜欢那样
I'd like that.
嘿 美女      嗨
Hey, gorgeous.        Hey.
听着 昨天的事 我很抱歉
Look. I'm sorry about yesterday.
别担心 相信我 显然其他人 也会犯相同的错误
Don't worry about it. Believe me. Apparently, other people have made the same mistake.
那好
Oh. Okay. Phew.
那你觉得我是哪里像?
So, uh, what do you think it is about me?
我不知道
I don't know what.
你就是有种
You just have a...
特质      特质，对，太好了
...a quality.        A quality. Right. Great.
太可惜了 因为你和罗威尔 会是很棒的一对
It's a shame, because you and Lowell would've made a great couple.
罗威尔? 金融服务部的罗威尔?
Lowell? Financial Services Lowell?
你认为我适合跟他在一起?
That's who you saw me with?
干嘛? 他很可爱啊
What? He's cute.
是啊
Well, yeah.
他又不是出纳处的布莱恩
He's not Brian in Payroll.
布莱是 ?
Is Brian...?
不 我不知道 重点是 如果你要撮合我跟某人
No. I don't know. The point is, if you were gonna set me up with someone...
我比较喜欢 你把我和他那样的人配在一起
...I'd like to think you'd set me up with somebody like him.
我认为你配不上布莱恩
Well, I think Brian's a little out of your league.
不好意思 你认为 我追不到布莱恩?
Excuse me. You don'tthink I could get a Brian?
因为我绝对可以追到布莱恩 相信我
Because I could get a Brian. Believe you me.
我真的不是同性恋
I'm really not.
这一件?
This one?
不好
No.
我已经给你们看过所有的衣服了
I've shown you every dress we have.
除非你们想让自己的母亲穿着柠檬黄色套装...
Unless you want you mother to spend eternity in a lemonyellow pantsuit...
不然就选紫红色
...go with the burgundy.
不管我们选什么 她都不会满意
Whatever we pick, she would've told us its the wrong one.
没错 那就选酒红色
You're right. We'll go with the burgundy.
选得好 我要出来了
A fine choice. I'm coming out.
等等 我们还需要鞋子
Wait. We need shoes.
好
Okay. Uh...
这些如何?
How about these?
那些是白天穿的鞋
That's really a day shoe.
那她去的地方每个人都穿着考究吗?
And where she's going, everyone else will be dressier?
可以看看有细跟的鞋吗?
Could we see something in a slimmer heel?
好了 我找不到紫红色的晚装鞋
Okay. I have nothing in an evening shoe in the burgundy.
不过有双银色的鞋 或许适合
I can show you something in a silver that may work.
不行 一定要紫红色
No, it really should be burgundy.
除非我们挑另一件洋装      对
Unless we go with a different dress.        Yes.
不 不 不 我看看
No, no, no. Watch this.
等等 我可以在后面找找
Wait, I may have something in the back.
天啊
Oh, my God.
没事吧 亲爱的
Is everything all right, dear?
没事
Yeah. Yeah.
只是外婆的东西
Just Nana's stuff.
大家怎么样? 都好了吗?
How we doing? You guys ready?
妈早上已经打过电话提醒我不要把头发绑起来
Mom already called me this morning to remind me not to wear my hair up.
你知道我的耳朵不是我最漂亮的部位吗
Did you know my ears were not my best feature?
有段时间我是这样认为的
Some days it's all I can think about.
抱歉我迟到 我找不到方向了
Hi. I'm sorry I'm late. I couldn't find my bearings.
你是说耳环吗?
Heh. You mean your earrings?
我说了什么?
What did I say?
就是这双鞋子吗?
Are these the shoes?
对，巴洛从意大利寄过来的
Yes. Paolo sent them from Italy.
干嘛? 我们...我们这里没有鞋子 还是...
What? We, uh, don't have shoes here or...?
早上好 准备好出发了吗?
Morning. We ready to go?
穿戴整齐之后 我们看起来都很棒吧
Don't we look nice all dressed up?
就是这种话 是吧
It's stuff like that, isn't it?
真的是很棒的仪式      的确
It was a beautiful service.        It really was.
过来 亲爱的
Come here, sweetheart.
你知道
You know...
我认为该是你 开始使用晚霜的时候了
I think it might be time for you to start using night cream.
干嘛?
What?
没什么 只是你的大衣很吵
Nothing. Just your overcoat sounds remarkably like Brent Musburger.
你看看 巨人队对牛仔队
Check it out. Giants/Cowboys.
你在葬礼时看美式足球赛?
You're watching football at a funeral?
不 这只是赛前分析 待会在宴会上才要看
No，it's the pregame. I'm gonna watch it at the reception.
你真是个可怕的 可怕的人
You're a frightening, frightening man.
噢 不会吧 巴洛送的新鞋
Oh, no. My new Paolo shoes.
希望鞋没坏
Oh. I hope they're not ruined.
天啊 真是美好的一天
God, what a great day.
干嘛? 我是说天气
What? Weather-wise.
我知道
I know.
空气 还有树木
The air, the trees.
虽然外婆走了 但是...生命...
Even though Nana's gone, there's something almost, life...
罗斯 你没事吧      罗斯！
Ross, are you okay?        Ross!
我没事
I'm fine. No. I'm fine.
只是
Just...
我最大的梦魇终于成真 不过…
having my worst fear realized, but...
不用担心 我只是看看 你是否肌肉痉挛
Don't worry. I'm just checking to see if the muscle's in spasm.
怎么 怎么样
What? What is it?
你的皮带环掉了一个
You missed a belt loop.
好了 是肌肉痉孪了
Okay, it's in spasm.
来了 亲爱的 给你
Here. sweetie. Here.
我打高尔夫球受伤时 用的就是这个
I took these when I had my golfing accident.
谢了 妈
Thanks. Mom.
不好意思
Sorry.
你好 我是安卓亚
Hi. I'm Andrea.
我是桃乐茜的女儿
I'm Dorothy's daughter.
你好 我是钱德 我不知道桃乐茜是谁
Hi, I'm Chandler and I have no idea who Dorothy is.
嘿 看看是谁起来了
Hey, look who's up.
嗨      你觉得如何?
Hey.        How do you feel?
我觉得很棒
I feel great.
I feel great. I feel great.
哇 那些药丸真的有用
Wow, those pills really worked, huh?
前两颗还好 但后两颗真的...
Yeah. Not the first two, but the second two...woooo...
我好爱你们
I love you guys.
你们最棒了 我好爱我妹妹
You guys are the greatest. I love my sister.
我好爱菲比
I love Pheobe.
真好      嘿，钱德
That's so nice.        Hey. Chandler.
嗨      我好爱你
Hey.        I love you, man.
听好 如果你想当同性恋 那就好好当吧
And listen, if you wanna be gay, be gay.
我无所谓
It doesn't matter to me.
你没说错
You were right.
瑞秋
Rachel. Rachel, Rachel.
我最爱你了
I love you the most.
嗯 那你知道我最爱谁吗?
Well, you know who I love the most?
不知道
No.
是你
You.
噢 你没听懂
Oh, you don't get it.
那是什么?
What do you got there?
只是...听力装置
Uh, just a, uh, hearing disability.
比分多少?
What's the score?
巨人队以17分比14分领先 第三节只剩三分钟
17/14, Giants. Three minutes to go in the third.
太好了
Beautiful.
菲比 你可以拿块饼干给我吗?
Pheobe, could you maybe hand me a cracker?
你外婆一定不会喜欢的
Your grandmother would've hated this.
当然 这是她的葬礼
Well, sure. What with it being her funeral and all.
不 我会一直听到她说
No,I'd be hearing about...
为什么没有蜜酿火腿?
...why didn't I get the honeyglazed ham?
或是我买的花不够 又或者是...
Or I didn't spend enough on flowers. If I spent more,she'd say...
何必浪费那么多钱? 我都死了
"Why waste your money? I don't need flowers,I'm dead."
听起来很像外婆的口气
That sounds like Nana.
你知道从小到大
Do you know what it's like to grow up...
和挑剔你每一句话的人生活在一起是什么滋味吗?
...with someone who is critical of every single thing you say?
我想像得到
I can imagine.
我告诉你 你妈妈我能变成
I tell you, it's a wonder your mother turned out...
这么乐观 积极向上的人 真是个奇迹
...to be the positive, life-affirming person she is.
是很神奇
That is a wonder.
妈 告诉我 如果可以重来
So tell me something, Mom. If you had to do it all over again...
如果此时此刻她在这里
I mean, if she was here right now...
你会告诉她吗?
...would you tell her?
告诉她什么?
Tell her what?
她如何使你抓狂 挑剔每一件小事
How she drove you crazy, picking on every little detail.
譬如说你的头发
Like your hair, for example.
我不太懂你在说什么?
I'm not sure I know what you're getting at.
你认为如果告诉她实情 情况会好一点吗?
Do you think things would have been better if you'd just told her the truth?
不会
No.
我认为某些事 还是不说会比较好
I think some things are better left unsaid.
家和万事兴
I think it's nicer when people just get along.
再来些酒吗
More wine, dear?
当然
Oh. I think so.
你戴这副耳环真好看
Those earrings look really lovely on you.
谢谢
Thank you.
是你的耳环
They're yours.
其实是外婆的
Actually, they were Nana's.
不
No!
真叫人难过
Now, I'm depressed.
比刚才还难过
Even more than I was.
这个裸体的小家伙是谁?
Hey, who's this little naked guy?
那个裸体的小家伙就是我
Uh, that little naked guy would be me.
看这小东西      没错
Look at the little thing.      Yes.
没关系 那是我的小弟弟
Yes, fine. That is my penis.
我们能成熟点儿吗?
Can we be grown-ups now?
这些人是谁?      考倒我了
Who are those people?        Got me.
中间那个是外婆
That's Nana right there in the middle.
我看看
Yeah, let's see.
我和大伙们摄于爪哇咖啡厅
"Me and the gang at Java Joe's."
莫妮卡 你看起来和你外婆好像
Wow. Monica, you look just like your grandmother.
她那时候几岁?
How old was she there?
看一下 1939年
Let's see. 1939.
24 25岁吧
Uh. Twenty four, twenty five.
看起来这帮人很开心
Huh. It looks like a fun gang.
你们快看 有莫妮卡裸体的照片
Ooh, look, look, look. I got Monica naked.
我看看
Let me see.
不 那个还是我
No, no. That would be me again.
我在尝试新事物
I'm, uh, just trying something.
嘿 罗威尔      嘿 钱德
Hey, Lowell.        Oh, hey, Chandler
金融服务处还好吗?
So how's it going in Financial Services?
简直是一团乱
It's like Mardi Gras without the paper mache heads.
你们呢?
How about you?
很好 听着
Good. Good. Listen, um, heh...
我不知道雪莉怎么跟你说我的事 但是…
I don't know what Shelly told you about me, but, uh...
我并不是
I'm not.
我知道 我也是这样跟她说的
I know. That's what I told her
真的吗?      对
Really?        Yeah.
你看得出来?
So you can tell?
八九不离十吧 大多数都可以 我们有种...雷达
Pretty much. Most of the time. We have a kind of radar...
所以你不认为我有...
So you don't think I have...
那种特质?
quality?
代表男同志发言 我得说没有
Speaking for my people, I'd have to say no.
对了 你的朋友 出纳处的布莱恩? 他是同志
By the way, your friend Brian from Payroll? He is.
他是?      对
He is?        Yep.
而且你绝对配不上他
And way out of your league.
配不上他
Out of my league.
我可以追到布莱恩的 如果我愿意的话
I could get a Brian. If I wanted to get a Brian, I could get a Brian.
嘿 布莱
Hey, Brian.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧